

Pat31477@yahoo.com | C: 973-534-7198 | Hillsborough, NJ 08844

Summary

Quality Assurance Tester offering 20 years in manual software testing. Collaborated daily with QA team to conduct testing, detect issues and resolve problems. Meticulously updated project documents to record status, results and findings. Well versed in both Agile and Waterfall methodologies.

Demonstrated success in gray, white and black box testing. Write and understand test cases, create test plans and identifying use cases. Comprehensive understanding of full software development life cycle.

Skills

- Sugar CRM
- Testing plans
- Quality assurance and control
- Bug tracking
- Technical support
- Customer service
- Software testing
- Quality assurance
- Software compiling and packaging in Visual Basic and Iava
- Perforce P4 (source control management system)
- VSS client
- MySQL and SQL tools such as WinSQL, Mascon, and SQLyog
- Microsoft Windows XP, 7, 8, and 10

- Unix shell, Solaris Unix shell
- Core FTP
- Putty
- MS Office, including Excel, Outlook, Visio and Word
- Six Sigma
- Software testing
- Configuration management
- CRM
- SCRUM
- Functional, Scripts
- Customer service excellence
- Product support

Experience

Autologue Computer Systems | Newton, New Jersey

Customer Support Representative 09/2015 - 05/2020

- Supporting role for all aspects of customer support including account relationship, issue resolution and customer satisfaction.
- Assists with the company's largest corporate clients.
- Troubleshoot/Debug customer software issues.
- Interface with customers and development/management during escalations and prepare action plans to address customer issues and concerns
- Worked on site with customers to provide real time support and ensure successful integration
- Participate in daily/weekly client production meetings
- Create knowledge based articles for customers and in house use
- Evaluated customer account information to assess current issues and determine potential solutions.
- Processed customer account changes.
- Upheld high standards of customer services by responding to inquiries, needs and problems.
- Delivered fast, friendly and knowledgeable service for routine questions

and service complaints.

• Documented conversations with customers to track requests, problems and solutions.

eBay Motors/WHI | Newton, New Jersey Configuration/Release Manager 01/2007 - 09/2015

- Utilize configuration management tools and deployment infrastructure to ensure alignment with business demands.
- Ownership of build, deployment and framework process to ensure fast and repeatable builds.
- Develop scripts and tools to enhance and improve the existing build and integration process.
- Responsible for maintenance of builds for assigned product(s).
- Work with project teams to determine an appropriate build schedule and then initiate the build and release process.
- Write installation scripts and projects for all software products.
- Develop, analyze and maintain tools that support processes for product release.
- Administration and maintenance of Source control repositories.
- Design and document processes for versioning, deployment and the migration of code between environments.
- Conduct branching and merging for multiple release versions of products.
- Create and Deploy software script packages to clients.
- Configure and maintain QA Testing environment.
- Deliver Source Code to clients.
- Train employees on the configuration and software release process.
- Worked with project stakeholders in QA, development and business analysis to achieve objectives.
- Identified, addressed and either resolved or escalated project issues.
- Maintained close connection with project personnel to quickly identify and resolve problems.

iCarz/WHI | Newton, New Jersey Quality Assurance Tester 04/2000 - 01/2007

- Analyze defined requirements for testability.
- Design and execute Quality Assurance test plan, including the creation of test cases.
- Design and execute User Acceptance test plan, where applicable.
- Conduct peer review of QA and User Acceptance Test plans.
- Assist with Development's unit integration testing, system testing, and system integration testing when scheduling permits and where applicable.
- Run regressive test systems and evaluate results.
- Execute functional, application, and performance tests.
- Troubleshoot and analyze defects found during testing cycles.
- Record, track and test defects to closure.
- Maintain software testing documentation including checklists, master file lists, standard test plans, test cases, and test scripts.
- Troubleshoot/Debug customer software issues.
- Interface with customers and development/management during escalations and prepare action plans to address customer issues and concerns.
- Supported the company in maintaining a work environment focused on quality, communication, collaboration, integration and teamwork.
- Reviewed project requirements to uncover bugs and resolve issues within a timely manner.

- Oversaw user acceptance testing and reporting to review software use by consumers in real-world scenarios.
- Planned, implemented and monitored software testing by coordinating with staff and holding test review meetings.
- Updated requirements traceability matrix to document requirement ID, type, description and test case status.
- Designed and updated test cases to complete consistent manual tests.
- Consulted with product owners and developers to fully understand intended features and functionality.
- Collaborated with management to establish testing plans develop improvement strategies.
- Drafted defect reports identifying problems and shared testing metrics with team to develop solutions.
- Worked with Agile and Scrum methodologies to accomplish project milestones and meet demanding timelines.
- Wrote and updated manual test cases for team use, maintaining optimal organization for maximum productivity.
- Oversee daily department functions.
- Inventory control.
- Associate supervision.
- Customer assistance.
- Associate reviews and coaching.
- Associate training.
- Department restructuring.
- Ensured that all employees within the Electronics and Automotive departments presented a positive, exemplary image to customers.
- Identified and diminished performance gaps by coaching and supervising subordinates.
- Resolved all customer complaints in a professional manner while prioritizing customer satisfaction.
- Fostered a positive work environment by consistently treating all employees and customers with respect and consideration.
- Assigned work to team members based on company needs, personal
- Balanced workloads to meet targets without overtaxing employees.
- Kept department on-target to meet sales and profit objectives by minimizing waste and pursuing revenue generation opportunities.
- Promoted high customer satisfaction by resolving problems with knowledgeable and friendly service.
- Cultivated talented team of departmental employees through outstanding mentoring, coaching and teaching skills.
- Oversaw efficient receiving and inventory management to keep stock within optimal levels.
- Enforced safety rules and other policies to protect employees and minimize company liability.
- Coached, trained and mentored new team members and manager trainees.
- Delegated work to staff, setting priorities and goals.
- Performed opening and closing duties as part of management team, including cash management.
- Greeted and assisted all customers daily in high-traffic retailer.

Wal-Mart. Inc | Newton, New Jersey **Department Manager**02/1998 - 04/2000

Education and Training

VM EDU

 ${\bf Six~Sigma~Yellow~Belt~Certification}$ in Six Sigma Yellow Belt 10/2018

VM EDU

 ${\bf SCRUM\ Master\ Certification}$ in SCRUM Master Agile Testing 10/2018

The CHUBB Institute -Parsipanny, NJ **CTS Certification** in Computer Tech Support 11/2000

- Graduated with honors
- Selected for tutoring program